Jenny T. Liang

Ph.D. Student

Carnegie Mellon University School of Computer Science Institute for Software Research <u>itliang@andrew.cmu.edu</u> <u>www.jennyliang.me</u> <u>♥ @jennytliang</u>

I research ways to make programming better for everyone by studying developers and programming communities as well as designing intelligent tools that make building software easier.

Education

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA Ph.D. in Software Engineering	2021 -
University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA B.S. in Computer Science, B.S. in Informatics (GPA: 3.77)	2015 - 2021
Research Experience	
Allen Institute of Artificial Intelligence, Mosaic Team Predoctoral Young Investigator, advised by Ronan Le Bras and Yejin Choi	2021 -
University of Washington , Information School, Code & Cognition Lab Undergraduate Research Assistant, advised by Amy J. Ko	2020 -

Microsoft Research, Software Analysis and Intelligence (SAINTES) Group
Undergraduate Research Intern, advised by Denae Ford Robinson and Thomas Zimmermann

Allen Institute of Artificial Intelligence, Mosaic Team 2020 - 2021

Undergraduate Research Intern, advised by Swabha Swayamdipta, Chandra Bhagavatula, and Yejin Choi

University of Washington, Computer Science & Engineering, Information and Communication 2019 - 2020 Technology for Development (ICTD) Lab

Undergraduate Research Assistant, advised by Spencer Sevilla and Kurtis Heimerl

Awards & Honors

Amaras & Honors	
National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellow (\$138,000 over 3 years)	2021
Computing Research Association Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Honorable Mention	2020
University of Washington Computer Science & Engineering Undergraduate Service Award Award to recognize 3 UW CSE undergraduates out of 2,000 students for their outstanding service to the department.	2020
Husky 100 Award to recognize 100 UW students out of 55,000 students in honor of their outstanding contributions to the university.	2020
Allen Institute of Artificial Intelligence Outstanding Engineer (\$12,000)	2019
Denice Dee Denton Scholarship (\$1,000) Departmental scholarship for students who show a commitment to a diverse student population.	2019
UW Academy Scholar	2015

Early entrance to the University of Washington at 16 years old.

Funding

IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering Student Mentoring Workshop Participant (\$1,075)	2022
UW CSE SIGCSE Travel Award (\$500)	2020
N2Women Mobicom Travel Grant (\$1,200)	2019
UW CSE Grace Hopper Conference Travel Award (\$1,200)	2019

Peer-Reviewed Publications (* denotes equal contribution)

Understanding Skills of OSS Contributors on GitHub

I.T. Liang, T. Zimmermann, D. Ford

ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE) 2022

Towards Mining OSS Skills from GitHub Activity

J.T. Liang, T. Zimmermann, D. Ford

IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering—New Ideas and Emerging Results (ICSE-NIER) 2022

An Exploratory Study of Sharing Strategic Programming Knowledge

M. Arab, T.D. LaToza, J. Liang, A.J. Ko

ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2022

HowToo: A Platform for Sharing, Finding, and Using Programming Strategies

M. Arab, J. Liang*, Y.K. Yoo*, A.J. Ko, T.D. LaToza

Visual Languages and Human-Centric Computing (VL/HCC) 2021

Whale Watching in Inland Indonesia: Analyzing a Small, Remote, Internet-Based Community Cellular Network

M. Johnson, <u>J. Liang</u>, M. Lin, S. Singanamalla, K. Heimerl

The Web Conference (WWW) 2021

Experiences: Design, Implementation, and Deployment of CoLTE, a Community LTE Solution

S. Sevilla, M. Johnson, P. Kosakanchit, <u>I. Liang</u>, K. Heimerl

ACM International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (Mobicom) 2019

An All-in-One Community LTE Network

S. Sevilla, M. Johnson, P. Kosakanchit, J. Liang, K. Heimerl

ACM International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (Mobicom) 2019

Preprints

Delphi: Towards Machine Ethics and Norms

Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA, USA.

L. Jiang, J.D. Hwang, C. Bhagavatula, R. Le Bras, M. Forbes, J. Borchardt, <u>J. Liang</u>, O. Etzioni, M. Sap, Y. Choi Under submission. <u>arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.07574</u>.

Invited Talks

Towards Mining OSS Skills from GitHub Activity (Poster) IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering 2022, Pittsburgh, PA, USA. Understanding Skills for OSS Communities (Talk) 05/2022

Interpreting Hate Speech Classifiers: Does dataset label space matter? (Talk) UW Undergraduate Research Symposium, Seattle, WA, USA.	05/2021
Explicit Programming Strategies (Talk) UW Undergraduate Research Symposium, Seattle, WA, USA.	05/2020
An All-in-One Community LTE Network (Demo) ACM International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking 2019, Los Cabos, Mexico.	
Selected Press	
WIRED. "This Program Can Give AI a Sense of Ethics—Sometimes."	10/2021
New York Times. "Can a Machine Learn Morality?"	11/2021
Teaching	
Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, University of Washington, Computer Science & Engineering Building Academic Success through Bottom-Up Computing (Introduction to Computer Systems), CSE 391B. (Sp 2020) Software Design & Implementation, CSE 331. (Au 2019, Wi 2020) Accelerated Introduction to Programming, CSE 143X. (Au 2018) Introduction to Programming II, CSE 143. (Sp 2018, Wi 2019, Sp 2019)	2018 - 2020
Service	
Student Leader, UW Undergraduate Research Program.	2021
Vice Chair (2020), Officer (2019), Representative (2021), UW CSE Student Advisory Council. Advocating for computer science students' needs and perspectives to faculty, staff, and administrators.	2019 - 2021
Industry Experience	
Uber , Developer Experience, Software Engineer Intern	2019
Apple, Mail Team, Software Engineer Intern	2019
Microsoft, Personal Bing, Software Engineer Intern	2019
Microsoft, Exchange Enterprise Cloud, Software Engineer Intern	2018
Microsoft, Workplace Analytics, Software Engineer Intern	2017
Microsoft, Office 365, Intern	2016